## Jan Kukielski, Tax Specialist

Poland, +48 576 784 353, jankukielski1@gmail.com

#### PROFILE

I'm an enthusiastic and dedicated tax specialist with almost 4 years of experience in the field of tax. The major part of my experience consists of tax returns from dividends, which were paid to investment funds. During that time I contributed to improving various process which led to significantly reduced processing times. At present, while working for Aon I am responsible for monitoring CIT of the companies entities within the EMEA region. The fluent knowledge of both Polish and English allows me to working within multinational environments and cooperate with teams around the world.

#### EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Sep 2023 — Present

### Tax Specialist, Aon

Kraków (remote)

- Assisting in managing and reviewing the monthly, quarterly and annual US GAAP corporate income tax
  provision in jurisdictions outside of the US.
- Supporting the preparation of documentation related to the Tax Reporting and local tax compliance requirements and processes.
- Assisting in the preparation of return-to-provision calculations for entities outside of the US.
- Assisting in the preparation of existing and emerging global tax reporting and compliance requirements, such as Country-by-Country Reporting.

Jan 2021 — Aug 2023

## Senior Tax Specialist, State Street

Gdańsk

- Working closely with VBA developers to create macros for multiple processes within the team. As a result the payment processes on various markets were automated, which contributed to a significant increase in the volume of work completed.
- Creating and implementing new processes and controls such as audit lists for all payments to decrease the
  amount of potential errors.
- Preparing reports for management containing overall results within the team (amount of processed payments, outstanding payments, potential delays and ongoing issues).
- Training new joiners by showing the entire process of payment processing both in the office and remotely.

May 2019 — Dec 2020

#### Junior Tax Specialist, State Street

Gdańsk

- Comparing and confirming data related to tax returns from dividends mainly with the use of MS Excel as
  well as internal company programs/databases.
- Cooperating with internal and external clients to solve any discrepancies occurring in the received reports.
- Processing tax return payments to investment funds.
- Solving any issues associated with the process of tax returns.

## EDUCATION

Oct 2018 — Jul 2021

# Bachelor's Degree, Wyższa Szkoła Bankowa w Gdańsku

Gdańsk

**English Studies** 

SKILLS

Time Management

Agile/Scrum

Ability to Work in a Team

Complex Problem Solving

Microsoft Office

Initiative

Communication

HOBBIES

Programming, sport and travel.

LANGUAGES

Polish

Native speaker

English

C2

COURSES

Jan 2022 — Jan 2023

JavaScript Developer, Coders Lab